filtrbox.com 2012-06-22

# Jive Software - Privacy Policy

## Privacy Policy

_Last updated December 29, 2011_

Jive Software, Inc. and its affiliated companies and subsidiaries (collectively referred to here as “we,” “our,” or “Jive”) created this Privacy Policy to inform our websites' users (including users of features and functionality on our websites), event registrants/participants, newsletter/information recipients, promotion participants, online community participants, those who purchase or inquire about our products and services, and others (collectively referred to as “customers”) about our practices regarding collection, use, and disclosure of personally identifiable information (“personal data”) that we collect from them through our website: www.jivesoftware.com and our service: Jive. The use of information collected through our service shall be limited to the purpose of providing the service for which the Client has engaged Jive Software, Inc.

While Jive's websites or other materials may include links or references to non-Jive websites, materials, or entities, this Privacy Policy does not apply to those non-Jive sites, materials, or entities unless otherwise indicated.

Jive Software, Inc. has been awarded TRUSTe's Privacy Seal signifying that this privacy policy and practices have been reviewed by TRUSTe for compliance with TRUSTe's [Program Requirements](http://www.truste.com/privacy-program-requirements/program_requirements_website_privacy.html) and the [TRUSTed Cloud Program Requirements](http://www.truste.com/privacy-program-requirements/trusted-cloud/index.html) including transparency, accountability and choice regarding the collection and use of your personal information. TRUSTe’s mission, as an independent third party, is to accelerate online trust among consumers and organizations globally through its leading privacy trustmark and innovative trust solutions. If you have questions or complaints regarding our privacy policy or practices, please contact us at privacy@jivesoftware.com. If you are not satisfied with our response you can contact [TRUSTe here.](http://watchdog.truste.com/pvr.php?page=complaint) The TRUSTe program does not cover information that may be collected offline or through our mobile applications.

Jive Software, Inc. complies with the U.S. - E.U. Safe Harbor and U.S. - Swiss Safe Harbor frameworks as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use and retention of personal data from the European Union member countries and Switzerland. Jive Software, Inc. has certified that it adheres to the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access, and enforcement. To learn more about the Safe Harbor program, and to view Jive Software, Inc. certification, please visit [www.export.gov/safeharbor](http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/ "Safe Harbor Certificate")

#### Your Consent

You should read this entire Privacy Policy before submitting information to Jive or using any Jive website. Whenever you submit information via a Jive website site or otherwise to Jive, whether online or offline, you consent to the collection, use, and disclosure of that information in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

#### COPPA Requirements 

Our websites are not directed to children and we do not knowingly collect any personally identifiable information from children under 13 years of age through our sites.

#### Information Collection and Use on the Jive Web site 

Jive may collect personal data from customers both online and offline. In many cases, such information will be collected directly from you, such as through a transaction or inquiry, or your submission of a form, registration, or communication to us. Information may also be gathered from third-party sources (including without limitation, opt-in lists, publicly available data, consumer reporting agencies, other companies, and referrals) and through your activities and interactions with us. We may combine data collected from these disparate sources unless we tell you otherwise. 

Jive collects personal data about its customers in a number of ways. In this section, we describe what types of personal data we collect, the ways we collect it, and how we use it. While we have tried to be complete, this list is not necessarily exhaustive, given that these activities can vary from time to time. 

The types of personal data typically collected by Jive may include the following, depending on your activities:

  * Contact information, including name, title, street address (home, work), postal code, country, telephone numbers (home, work, cell, etc.), email address (home, work), company name, and other similar information.
  * Personal/demographic information, including gender, level of education and the like.
  * Authentication information, including user IDs, log-in names, passwords, password reminders, etc. (in addition to other personal data such as contact information and the like).
  * Transactional information, including products or services you inquire about, or request; payment information, including your credit card type, number, expiration date and billing address for the card.
  * User content, including information provided when you use one of our online communities, forums or other online means of communications, and all other user submissions and content you provide.
  * If you choose to use our referral service to invite a friend to the Jive community, we will ask you for your friend's email address. We will automatically send your friend a one-time email inviting him or her to visit the site. Jive stores this information for the sole purpose of sending this one-time email and tracking the success of our referral program.

Your friend may contact us at [privacy@jivesoftware.com](mailto:privacy@jivesoftware.com "Email Privacy\(at\)Jivesoftware.com") to request that we remove this information from our database.

#### What additional Information Does The Jive Service Collect From Corporate Clients?

When operating as a data processor for our corporate clients the following will apply to our Service:

We will also collect information about others from corporate clients such as:

  * The name and email address of individuals to be added to the Service.

We use this information to:

  * Allow corporate clients to email new users of the Service notification of account activation
  * Administer your corporate service account

Jive collects information under the direction of its corporate clients, and has no direct relationship with the individuals whose personal data it processes. Jive works with its corporate clients to help them provide notice to their customers concerning the purpose for which personal information is collected.

#### Accessto Data Controlled by our Corporate Clients. 

Jive has no direct relationship with the individuals whose personal data it processes. An individual who seeks access, or who seeks to correct, amend, or delete inaccurate data should log into their account and make the appropriate changes or deletions, or direct their query to their corporate administrator (the data controller). If the Corporate Client requests Jive remove the data, we will respond to their request within 30 business days.

#### Additional Information 

As you use our websites or services, some information can be “passively” collected using various technologies, such as cookies, web beacons, and navigational data collection (clickstream, log files, server logs, etc.). Your Internet browser automatically transmits some of this information, such as the URL of the website you just visited and the Internet Protocol (IP) address and browser version currently being used by your computer. Such technologies help us to keep track of your interactions with our websites and services, and provide you with a more customized experience, and may include referring/exit pages, platform type, date/time stamp, and number of clicks.

As is the case with many websites, Jive websites and services may use cookies and other automated information collection means. Cookies are information about you from the website that is stored on your browser or hard drive. We do not link the information we store in cookies to any personally identifiable information you submit while on our site. Cookies save you time because you do not need to manually re-enter the information stored on your hard drive. Cookies also help us upgrade the website by showing when and how users use the website. You can set your browser to notify you when a cookie is sent or refuse cookies altogether, but certain features of Jive websites might not work without cookies.

The use of cookies by our service providers are not covered by our privacy statement. We do not have access or control over these cookies.

Jive websites and services may also use IP addresses for the same purposes identified above, as well as to analyze trends, administer the website, track users' movements, gather broad demographic information for aggregate use and to confirm that a particular individual affirmed his/her consent to specific legal terms (e.g. our clickwrap license agreement).

We may use web beacons (also known as Internet tags or clear GIFs) on our websites and services to access and set cookies and otherwise help us to better understand how users are utilizing our websites. Information provided by the web beacon includes the computer's IP address, the type of browser being used, and the time that the web beacon was viewed. We may also use web beacons in emails and newsletters so that we know when such communications have been opened and to otherwise help us tailor our communications to individual users. 

We use local shared objects, also known as Flash cookies, to store your preferences relating to video content we provide on the Jive Software Web site. Third Parties, with whom we partner to provide this feature, use Flash cookies to collect and store information.

Flash cookies are different from browser cookies because of the amount of, type of, and how data is stored. Cookie management tools provided by your browser will not remove Flash cookies. To learn how to manage privacy and storage settings for Flash cookies click [here](http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager.html#117118). Finally, we also monitor the performance of our services and our websites in order to manage, maintain, and improve our services and websites. We (or our third party providers) may use tools to help prevent and block “spam” communications, viruses, spyware, and other harmful or unwanted communications and programs on the website. These tools may automatically scan any content you upload through the websites (or using functionality available via the websites) in order to help us protect you and the website against these harmful or unwanted communications and programs. However, these tools do not collect or disclose personally identifiable information about you. 

Jive uses personal data about customers for a wide range of purposes. We use it to respond to your requests (including requests for newsletter subscriptions, materials, support, and so on); to provide products or services that you have ordered; to process your order transactions and contact you regarding your order; to provide materials you have requested; to invite and help you participate in a range of online and offline events, and/or activities; to allow you to post information and other content online (including in response to other postings); to improve our products, services, and websites; to follow up with you after you have communicated with us or submitted information to us; to send promotional communications or offers (unless you have requested that we not send such communications); for marketing and research purposes; for internal and/or external training, quality assurance, and other purposes (including without limitation, call center recordings); to allow you to contact another person; for legal and contractual reasons; to address your interests and concerns; and as otherwise specified in this Privacy Policy and/or at the point of personal data collection. Here are some additional details on our use of the data we collect: 

  * Conducting and following up on transactions. Jive may use personal information such as name, title, street address, phone number, email address, title, and/or company name to conduct transactions with you, process your order, contact you about your order, and so on. 
  * Registration (memberships, accounts (i.e., log-ins and passwords, etc.)) and participation in online communities/provision of user-generated content. Customers may be given an opportunity to register for a variety of reasons, including to receive promotional communications/offers; to join/participate in an online community, blog, or other interactive areas or to otherwise provide user-generated content (such as posting favorite photos/videos/audio recordings, providing testimonials, sharing experiences about Jive products, etc.); to attend an event (e.g., a conference); and so on. Such activities may entail collection of name, title, contact information, birth date, user name and password, email address, experiences with Jive products, and personal information/preferences related to the subject matter of the particular activity. In some cases, you will select a user ID and password when you register, and you will use this to gain access to certain registration-restricted areas. Note that using a Jive website as a registered user enables information that is passively collected as you navigate the website to be associated with personal data actively collected from you on the website. Jive may use and/or disclose any personal data captured in an online community. You are responsible for any postings you make in any online community. Before submitting any user-generated content, you should review and adhere to any applicable Terms of Use found at [www.jivesoftware.com/legal](http://www.jivesoftware.com/legal) and also keep in mind that anything you make available as a participant in an online community or submit for posting by Jive may be made available for others to see; you should therefore carefully consider whether you wish to submit personal data, or any data, for these purposes. Any content submitted to an online community will be subject to the applicable Terms of Use located at www.jivesoftware.com/legal; therefore, please read such terms carefully prior to submitting or posting any information. We reserve the right to not post or make available and/or remove any data submitted to us, as further described in the applicable Terms of Use at www.jivesoftware.com/legal. To request removal of your personal information from our blog or community forum, contact us at privacy@jivesoftware.com . In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why.
  * To contact us with questions, comment, or concerns. We provide a number of ways for you to contact us to ask questions, provide comments, or share concerns. This may occur, for example, via the “contact us” sections on Jive websites, or postal mail. Depending on the circumstances, we may collect your name, title, contact information, message type, case number (if tied to a previous issue), comments, and other types of data relevant to the specific situation (e.g., product involved, use of the product, any problems with the product, and the like). 
  * To provide materials you request. We provide a number of ways for you to request materials from us, such as newsletters, blog/rss feeds, brochures, product literature, and the like. Jive may collect and use contact name, title, contact information, demographic information, preferences, and other information relevant to responding to your request. 
  * For marketing purposes (unless you have told us otherwise). We may use your contact information to tell you about other products and services that we believe might be of interest. If at any time you do not want communications for promotional purposes, please let us know (see the “It's Your Choice” section of the Privacy Policy).

_This list is for illustrative purposes only and should not be considered exhaustive._

We will share your personal information with third parties only in the ways that are described in this privacy statement. We do not sell your personal information to third parties.

We may disclose personal data you provide to our affiliates and partners and to consultants, service providers, and contractors that we use to support our business and operations (e.g., delivery services, financial institutions, fulfillment services, technical support, advertising, public relations, media and marketing services, legal services, call-in centers, e-commerce and other web-related services such as web hosting and web monitoring services, and event-related services such as online and offline data capture services) who have agreed to keep the information confidential and use it only to provide the applicable service(s). In some cases, we work with other companies who help to gather information from you or help us to communicate with you. 

We may also disclose personal data to third parties (including without limitation, governmental agencies) if required to do so by law, regulation, or court order; to respond to governmental and/or law enforcement requests; to identify, contact, or bring legal action against someone who may be causing injury to or interfering with our (or others') rights or property; to support any claim, defense, or declaration in a case or before any jurisdictional and/or administrative authority, arbitration, or mediation panel; or in connection with disciplinary actions/investigations. Likewise, we may disclose personal data to third parties in connection with the sale, assignment, or other transfer of Jive, its business or the website to which such data applies. In the event that Jive goes through a business transition, such as a merger, acquisition by another company or sale of a portion of its assets, our customers' personal information may be part of the assets transferred. Customers will be notified via prominent notice on our website prior to a change of ownership or control of their personal information. If, as a result of the business transaction, your personally identifiable information will be used in a manner materially different from that stated at the time of collection, you will be notified consistent with our Privacy Policy.

The recipients of customers' personal data, and more generally these disclosures, may be located in the United States or other jurisdictions that might not provide a level of protection equivalent to the laws in your jurisdiction. By submitting personal data to Jive, you consent to the transfer of such personal data outside your jurisdiction. 

We may make full use of all information that is de-identified or otherwise not in personally identifiable form, including without limitation, user-generated content. We will not, however, make use of any content you upload to a virtual online community that you or your organization has created through the use of our fee-based licensed products and services. 

#### Security

Jive takes appropriate steps to protect personal data from loss, misuse, and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, or destruction, whether in transmission or storage. When you enter sensitive information (such as a credit card number) on our order forms, we encrypt the transmission of that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL). Please keep in mind, however, that there is no such thing as perfect security, and no Internet transmission is ever completely secure or error-free. Moreover, you are responsible for maintaining the confidentiality of any user name and password you use. If you have any questions about security on our Web site, you can contact us via the contact information below. 

#### It's Your Choice: Contact Preferences 

We want to keep in touch with you in ways that you find to be beneficial. By submitting personal contact information, you are agreeing that we may communicate with you via email, telephone, direct mail, and/or other means of communication. If you don't want us to use your contact information for promotional purposes (such as to tell you about other products and services that might be of interest), please tell us that when you provide your contact information. You can also let us know your preference later by contacting us as specified in the “Contact Us” section below, or by following the unsubscribe instructions in various communications that we may send you. Keep in mind that these preferences regarding promotional contacts do not mean that we might not contact you for other reasons, such as those related to an order you placed, an inquiry you made, a newsletter to which you may have subscribed, a membership you undertook, an event for which you registered, a legally required notice, and so on. 

#### Privacy Controls 

After you have registered for an account on our service you may adjust your privacy settings by logging into your account and making the appropriate changes.

#### Re-Targeted Advertising 

Re-Targeted advertising uses information collected on an individual's web browsing behavior such as the pages they have visited or the searches they have made. This information is then used to display ads. The information collected is only linked to an anonymous cookie ID (alphanumeric number); it does not include any information that could be linked back to a particular person, such as their name, address or credit card number. The information used for targeted advertising either comes from Jive or through third party website publishers. If you would like to opt out of re-targeted advertising from Jive that occurs when visiting our third party advertising publishers, please click [here](http://preferences.truste.com/truste/ "Opt Out Link"). Please note this does not opt you out of being served advertising. You will continue to receive generic ads.

#### Testimonials 

We post customer testimonials/comments/reviews on our web site which may contain personally identifiable information. We do obtain the customer's consent via email prior to posting the testimonial to post their name along with their testimonial. If you want your testimonial removed please contact us via the information below. 

#### Your California Privacy Rights 

California Civil Code Section 1798.83 permits customers who are California residents to request that Jive not share their personal data with third parties for such parties' direct marketing purposes. To make such a request, send an e-mail with “California Privacy” in the subject line to [privacy@jivesoftware.com](mailto:%20privacy@jivesoftware.com "Jive Privacy Email") or write to us:

**Attention: Consumer Relations — CA Privacy Issues**  
Attn: Jive Software – General Counsel  
915 SW Stark Street, Suite 400   
Portland, OR 97205  

#### Access

To keep personal data provided by you accurate, current, and complete, please contact us as specified in the “Contact Us” section or by making the change within your Jive community profile page after login into your account. We can then take appropriate steps to update or correct such information in our possession, or to delete your information from our contact list. We will respond to your request to access within 30 days.

We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements. 

If you wish to delete your Jive community corporate profile you may contact your Community Administrator. If you wish to delete your profile from the JiveSoftware.com community you may contact us at [concierge@jivesoftware.com. ](mailto:%20concierge@jivesoftware.com "Jive Concierge Email ")

If you wish to request the deletion of an unauthorized corporate profile you may contact your Community Administrator. If you wish to request the deletion of an unauthorized profile from the JiveSoftware.com community you may contact us at [concierge@jivesoftware.com. ](mailto:%20concierge@jivesoftware.com "Jive Concierge Email ")

#### Contact Us

If you have questions or concerns related to this Privacy Policy or Jive's information practices, would like to update or correct information you have provided, or would like to opt out of future communications, please contact us as follows:

**Webmaster, Jive.**  
915 SW Stark Street, Suite 400   
Portland, OR 97205.   

Or email [concierge@jivesoftware.com. ](mailto:%20concierge@jivesoftware.com "Jive Concierge Email ")

####  Changes to This Privacy Policy 

If this Privacy Policy changes, the revised policy will include a new effective date and will be posted on this page. If we make any material changes we will notify you by email (sent to the e-mail address specified in your account) or by means of a notice on this Site prior to the change becoming effective. Be sure to check the Privacy Policy whenever you submit personal data. The effective date of this Privacy Policy is the date first set forth above. Your continued use of Jive website(s) or services following the posting of any amendment will constitute your acceptance of that amendment.

325 Lytton Avenue, Suite 200, Palo Alto, CA 94301 | Sales: 1-503-972-6143 | General: 1-503-295-3700   
© Copyright 2000—2012 Jive Software. The new way to business.™ All rights reserved.
